# John Nguyen

# Full Stack Developer

: nguyentuanj@gmail.com in: <u>dev-john-nguyen</u> : <u>dev-john-nguyen</u> : <u>athletecoder.com</u>







#### **About Me**

I'm a Full Stack Developer with 3 years of experience building efficient and sustainable SAAS applications. Currently working as a Full Stack Developer on a SAAS that helps businesses craft pricing strategies with AI where business have seen up to 10% lift in revenue. Since joining the Pricing Catalyst BCG team, I'm responsible for our Localized Assortment module and 10+ React reusable components. I've collaborated on various projects with multiple agile development teams of 5+ engineers. I'm seeking new opportunities to apply and further my skills as a Full Stack Developer.

## **Technical Skills**

#### Languages

- JavaScript and TypeScript
- Python
- SOL
- HTML/CSS

#### Frameworks/Libraries

- React and React Native
- Node.js and Express.js
- Django, FastAPI, and Flask
- PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and Firebase

### **Experience**

#### **Full Stack Developer**

The Boston Consulting Group (BCG)

Feb 2022 - Present

- Built, maintained, and enhanced 15+ React reusable components that were heavily used throughout the MVP.
- Utilized raw SQL and Sqlalchemy's ORM to perform efficient create, read, update, and delete actions to the database.
- Implemented 10+ React UI that contained features such as drag-and-drop and interactive charts.
- Participated in pair programming to implement features or debug issues.
- Redesigned 10+ Postgres database tables in production and development environments to meet data requirements.
- Enforced infrastructure guidelines through development reviews and providing feedback to developers.
- Configured 10+ server-side endpoints that authenticate user access and validate data using FastAPI.
- Enhanced app performance by utilizing lazy loading, memoization, caching, and efficient state management in React.
- Collaborated with an agile development team of 10+ engineers to build an MVP retail assortment application.
- Covid, Volunteered @ People's Voice on Climate and continued to apply my technological skills to personal projects (see below).

#### **Software Engineer**

Fast Enterprises Aug 2019 - Oct 2020

- Software engineer on the Louisville, KY tax project.
- Simultaneously collaborated with our client and vendors to implement tailored features.
- Coordinated with a team of 5+ engineers to configure and improve software features.
- Integrated an electronic filing service where 100,000+ residents used the service to file their taxes.
- Presented demos to our client for new software features.
- In pursuit of a professional American football career. Landed an opportunity in Cairo, Egypt in 2019.

#### **Education**

# **Management Information Systems**

University of Montana

Aug 2013 - Jan 2018

# **Projects**

#### Softlete

Training Log Application for Athletes

https://www.softlete.com/

- Technology Stack: React Native, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, and Firebase.
- Provided users with numerous services that can enhance their training and improve their personal health.
- Used Socket.IO for live messaging, updates and notifications.
- Integrated Stripe's and Apple Store's payment services.
- Incorporated data from Apple HealthKit's API.

#### Habts

Habit Tracker Application

https://habt-b0f23.web.app/

- Technology Stack: React Native and Firebase.
- Provided users with a fun and unique way to track their daily habits.
- Integrated Apple Store's payment services.

# **Extracurricular**

#### **Technology Specialist**

People's Voice on Climate

Feb 2021 - Present

**Performance Athletic Trainer** 

Freelance

Jan 2021 - Present Jan 2019 - Jul 2019

**Professional American Football Player** MSA Tigers (Cairo, Egypt)

**Collegiate Student Athlete (American Football Player)** 

University of Montana Aug 2013 - Dec 2017